Herbert Waide Hemphill
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Photographs, 1876-1997, Series 8:; (Box 19-24, 29; 5.5 linear feet)
  - Photographs of Artwork (Box 20)
    - Art Work in Illinois, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Art Work in Louisiana, 1975-1976, undated, (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 26-28)
    - Art Work in Maine, 1977-1978 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Art Work in Massachusetts, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Art Work in Michigan, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Art Work in Mississippi, 1975-1976, undated (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Art Work in Nebraska, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Art Work in New Jersey, 1975-1979 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Art Work in New Mexico, 1971-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 35-36)
    - Art Work in New York, 1969-1979, undated, (7 folders) (Box 22, Folder 37-43)
    - Art Work in Ohio, 1977, undated (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Art Work in Oklahoma, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Art Work in Pennsylvania, 1975, undated (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Art Work in Rhode Island, undated (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Art Work in Texas, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Art Work in Vermont, undated (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Art Work in West Virginia, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Art Work in Wisconsin, 1977-1981, undated, (6 folders) (Box 22, Folder 51-56)
    - "North Country" Art Work, 1979, (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 57-59)
    - Art Work in Canada, 1975-1977, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 60-61)
    - Outdoor Art in Unidentified Locations, 1971-1980, undated, (2 folders) (Box 22, Folder 62-63)
    - Art Work on Paper, 1967-1990, (12 folders) (Box 22, Folder 64-75)
    - Portrait Paintings of Children and Families by Unidentified Artists, 1970-1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 76-78)
    - Portrait Paintings of Women by Unidentified Artists, 1959-1983, undated, (4 folders) (Box 22, Folder 79-82)
    - Portrait Paintings of Men by Unidentified Artists, 1972-1977, undated, (4 folders) (Box 22, Folder 83-86)
    - Miscellaneous Paintings by Unidentified Artists, 1959-1986, undated, (7 folders) (Box 23, Folder 1-7)
    - Miscellaneous Murals by Unidentified Artists, 1971-1979, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Sculpture in Human Forms by Unidentified Artists, 1970-1986, undated, (21 folders) (Box 23, Folder 9-29)
    - Miscellaneous Sculpture in Animal Forms by Unidentified Artists, 1967-1985, undated, (7 folders) (Box 23, Folder 30-36)
    - Miscellaneous Sculpture in Bird Forms by Unidentified Artists, 1975-1977, undated, (5 folders) (Box 23, Folder 37-41)
    - Miscellaneous Sculpture in Fish Forms by Unidentified Artists, 1975-1983, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23, Folder 42-43)
    - Miscellaneous Canes by Unidentified Artists, 1975-1983, undated, (4 folders) (Box 23, Folder 44-47)
    - Miscellaneous Sculpture by Unidentified Artists, 1969-1986, undated, (8 folders) (Box 24, Folder 1-8)
    - Miscellaneous Signs by Unidentified Artists, 1975-1983, undated, (5 folders; oversized material housed in Box 29) (Box 24, Folder 9-13)
    - Art Work for the Circus by Unidentified Artists, 1963-1975, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 14-15)
    - Miscellaneous Collages and Assemblages by Unidentified Artists, 1975-1980, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Needlework by Unidentified Artists, 1972-1984, undated, (4 folders) (Box 24, Folder 17-20)
    - Miscellaneous Ceramic Art Work by Unidentified Artists, 1974-1985, undated, (5 folders) (Box 24, Folder 21-25)
    - Miscellaneous Glass Art Work by Unidentified Artists, 1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 24, Folder 26-27)
    - Miscellaneous Architecture by Unidentified Artists, 1970-1984, undated, (5 folders) (Box 24, Folder 28-32)
    - Miscellaneous Furniture by Unidentified Artists, 1968-1986, undated, (3 folders) (Box 24, Folder 33-35)
    - Slides of Art Work from Carousel 1, 1969-1988, undated (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Slides of Art Work from Carousel 2, 1971-1985, undated (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Slides of Art Work from Carousel 3, 1974-1975, undated (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Slides of Art Work from Carousel 4, 1975-1988, undated (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Slides of Art Work from Carousel 5, 1977-1988, undated (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Slide File of Miscellaneous Art Work, 1978, (3 folders) (Box 24, Folder 41-43)
    - Slides of Miscellaneous Art Work from the Carl Hammer Gallery, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Photograph File of Miscellaneous Art Work, undated (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Contact Sheets of Miscellaneous Art Work, undated (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Photographs of Miscellaneous Art Work, undated (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - Negatives of Miscellaneous Art Work, undated, (4 folders) (Box 24, Folder 48-51)
    - Eight Photographs of Exhibition at J. J. Steakhouse, undated, (from Box 13, Folder 16) (Box 29)
    - Oversized Photograph of Sign by Unidentified Artist, undated, (from Box 24, Folder 9) (Box 29)
- Sound and Video Recordings, 1986-1991, Series 9:; (Box 25-26; 13 folders)
  Sound and video recordings consist of a cassette recording from Hemphill's phone answering machine; audio cassettes of interviews with and concerning Hemphill, artists St. EOM and Robert E. Smith, and the tour narration for Smithsonian exhibition Made With Passion; and video recordings about Hemphill and artists Gayleen Aiken, Miller and Bryant, and Malcah Zeldis, and miscellaneous African American artists. There is also a video recording of Hemphill's travels to Melanesia and Papua New Guinea.
  - Micro-Cassette from Phone Answering Machine, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Audio-Cassette "A Message for Bert Hemphill" and "Swing of the 30s, Etc.," undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Audio-Cassette "Uncle Bert's Antique Shop" with Notes and Photograph of Hemphill with Art Work, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Audio-Cassette "Tom Patterson Channels St. EOM" and "Alex Chilton - Mix," undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Audio-Cassettes of Robert E. Smith Discussing His Paintings, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Audio-Cassettes of Tour Narration for Exhibition Made With Passion at National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Audio-Cassette Interview with Hemphill for University of Kentucky Oral History of 20th Century Folk Art, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Videotape "Gayleen" Concerning Gayleen Aiken, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Videotape "Mind's Eye Demo" Concerning African American Artists, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Videotape Interview with Hemphill by Charles Kuralt, CBS Television, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Videotape of Hemphill on CBS Sunday Morning News and Material Concerning Malcah Zeldis; Videotape Concerning Malcah Zeldis, 1987, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Videotape Material Concerning Miller & Bryant, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Videotape of Travel to Melanesia and Papua New Guinea Sponsored by American Museum of Natural History, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Artifacts, 1968-1995, Series 10:; (Box 26, 30; 0.7 linear feet)
  Miscellaneous artifacts include wooden "fringe" pieces from cigar store figures, ceramic fragments from a sword handle, a lock of horse hair, a hand-painted View Master viewer containing a disc of photographs of artists with their work including Vollis Simpson and Mary Frances Whitfield, and a teacher's kit Little Adventures in Art containing phonograph albums and film strips of slides showing art work in animal and bird forms.
  - Wooden "Fringe" Pieces from Cigar Store Figures, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Ceramic Fragments from a Sword Handle, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Lock of Horse Hair, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Hand-Painted View Master Viewer from Opening of American Visionary Art Museum in Baltimore, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Teacher's Little Adventures in Art Kit, 1968 (Box 30)